<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: weekly | The Lean Way on Music]]></title>
  <link href="http://leomrocha.github.io//github/blog/categories/weekly/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://leomrocha.github.io//github/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-07T19:00:25+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://leomrocha.github.io//github/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Leo Panigo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Last Week Sumup]]></title>
    <link href="http://leomrocha.github.io//github/blog/2014/08/30/last-week-sumup/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-30T11:16:58+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://leomrocha.github.io//github/blog/2014/08/30/last-week-sumup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m making this posts so I can learn more and better, and this week has been quite interesting.</p>

<p>The word <strong>lean</strong> in the blog theme is not because it should be easy, or fast, or no waste. But because the goal is to minimize the non-useful things, processes and be able to iterate <strong>fast</strong> and discard things that are not working.</p>

<p>What I&rsquo;ve found out this week is that is not necesary the best idea to write a blog post per video in the lessons.</p>

<p>The second week of taking lessons was really interesting, I&rsquo;ve made lots of progress on my music just in this two weeks that I am really motivated to keep on studying.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m still too impulsive and I have to improve my discipline with music.
I&rsquo;m used to playingwith my guitar, but discipline to actually study music is not my strongest point.</p>

<p>My new piano arrived Thursday night, and after that I was compeltely distracted with trying things, reading the manual, connecting it to the computer, etc. Luckily there are two friends at home now and both play piano well, so I&rsquo;ve been able to listen to nice things.</p>

<p>I tried playing some things. I was amazed how much could I really understand and do! I was waiting for not being able to do anything at all, but at least I&rsquo;ve been able to play a couple of melodies by ear, and start playing the first exercise of one of Czerny&rsquo;s piano methods!</p>

<p>I tested the USB-MIDI interface, is working great, and I&rsquo;m trying to find out how to build something that will help me in my learning path with it now. It will be web and I hope will be useful for other people too.</p>

<p>So, going to last week&rsquo;s goals:</p>

<p><strong>Last week goals:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Do all the lessons of week 2 of both courses &ndash;> DONE</li>
<li>Write posts that include all the theory of both courses up to the end of lesson 2 &ndash;> DONE (in a different way that the planned)</li>
<li><p>Having practiced 15 minutes every day (playing for fun doesn&rsquo;t count) &ndash;> MMMM, I&rsquo;ve practiced but not enough.</p></li>
<li><p>Having in paper (or in the computer) a detail of the tools (at least ear training and scale practice tools) &ndash;> plan changed, will do something more basic and easier first.</p></li>
<li>Having a decition and action plan written down for which tool to start working on next &ndash;> Changed, will create a web version of VMPK, but with synesthesia and be able to extend it for the learning tools later.</li>
<li>Having fixed the problem I found in musicpaste, as extra, having added (or started) working on another feature on the TODO list &ndash;> DONE, the fix. No extra</li>
</ul>


<h2>What&rsquo;s next</h2>

<p>So, I&rsquo;ve written down my sumup, now the important part that follows, the <strong>ACTIONS</strong> to take for next week.</p>

<h3>Education</h3>

<ul>
<li>Keep on doing the lessons</li>
<li>Watch one or two videos (if they seem to be related) and write a blog post for each on the theory</li>
<li>Start writing down the exercises and drills that I do for the Musicianship course and post them. Do this after each video where practice is involved.</li>
<li>Warm-up better before starting to play</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Success measures:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Do all the lessons of week 3 of both courses</li>
<li>Write posts that include all the theory of both courses up to the end of lesson 3</li>
<li>Write down at least 2 drills for piano and 2 for guitar.</li>
<li>Having practiced 15 minutes every day (playing for fun doesn&rsquo;t count)</li>
</ul>


<h3>Services</h3>

<ul>
<li>Start the WMPK page (VMPK web port for Chrome)</li>
<li>Make one improvement to <a href="http://musicpaste.com" title="MusicPaste">MusicPaste</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Success measures:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Having a simple AngularJS web page that can read and show on screen the midi input from the piano and can send midi instructions to the piano.</li>
<li>Having added (or started if it&rsquo;s complex) one feature in the TODO list</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
