<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: study, | The Lean Way on Music]]></title>
  <link href="http://leomrocha.github.io//github/blog/categories/study/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://leomrocha.github.io//github/"/>
  <updated>2014-09-07T19:00:25+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://leomrocha.github.io//github/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Leo Panigo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Studying Piano - Czerny Op.599 - 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://leomrocha.github.io//github/blog/2014/09/07/studying-piano-czerny-op-dot-599-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-09-07T16:28:30+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://leomrocha.github.io//github/blog/2014/09/07/studying-piano-czerny-op-dot-599-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Music inspires a passion that cannot be explained by words</strong></p>

<h1>Starting from the beginning</h1>

<p>As an amateur guitar player, I&rsquo;ve spent many years <em>&ldquo;playing&rdquo;</em> without actually knowing what was I doing.
I have a nice music intuition, so I&rsquo;ve been able to pull up with <em>learning by ear</em> and with <em>TABs</em>
But after a while I hitted a roadblock, and what blocked me was the lack of understanding of the music.</p>

<p>The conclusion:</p>

<p>I should start studying music theory, and getting to deeply understand it.</p>

<p>So, I started a few weeks ago with a couple of online courses, I repeat here the links:</p>

<ol>
<li>Developing Your Musicianship &ndash; Cursera &ndash; Berklee College of Music &ndash; <a href="https://class.coursera.org/musicianship-002">https://class.coursera.org/musicianship-002</a></li>
<li>Fundamentals of Music Theory &ndash; Cursera &ndash; University of Edinburg &ndash; <a href="https://class.coursera.org/musictheory-001">https://class.coursera.org/musictheory-001</a></li>
</ol>


<p>Starting from the beginning allowed me to improve a lot in a few weeks.</p>

<h1>Learning piano</h1>

<p>For a long time I&rsquo;ve been dreaming of a piano. Piano and violin are two instruments that caught my attention since I was a toddler, but I haven&rsquo;t had the chance to do it. I got a guitar instead (and now I <strong>love</strong> guitars too).</p>

<p>So I bought the piano (thanks to all the ones who participated to help me buy this as a birthday gift! specially my girlfriend whom made the whole organization for it) and now the question was:</p>

<p>Do I keep on doing the same thing? or should I actually start from the beginning?</p>

<p>I decided I wanted to do it well, from the begining. And talking to a (pianist) friend of mine, she recommended <strong>Czerny, First Teacher of the Piano</strong></p>

<p>Czerny was a prodigy in music and also great music teacher.
Among his  teachers we can name Bethoven, Salieri and Hummel and Clementi.
Also, most of the greatest clasic musicians can be traced back to Czerny</p>

<p>More about <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carl_Czerny" title="Carl Czerny">Carl Czerny</a> on Wikipedia</p>

<p>So I took her advice and started from the first exercise in the book.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s in the public domain, you can find it here: <a href="http://imslp.org/wiki/Practical_Exercises_for_Beginners,_Op.599_%28Czerny,_Carl%29">Practical Exercises for Beginners Op. 599</a></p>

<p><a href="http://imslp.org">IMSLP</a> is a great website for finding public domain music sheets.</p>

<p>So let&rsquo;s go to today&rsquo;s subject.</p>

<h2>Czerny Op. 599 &ndash; First exercise</h2>

<p>I started trying to read for the right and left hand and then going on with the whole exercise.</p>

<p>Even though I&rsquo;ve been able to read and do some things, this way didn&rsquo;t work as expected, and I kept on repeating many mistakes.</p>

<p>So I decided I&rsquo;ll analyze the exercise to understand it better,</p>

<p>I could extract the following facts:</p>

<ul>
<li>It&rsquo;s in <strong>C Major</strong></li>
<li>The <strong>tonic</strong> is <strong>C Major</strong></li>
<li>The mode is <strong>ionian</strong> because of the <strong>Tonic</strong></li>
<li>The clef for the right and left hand is the <strong>trebble</strong> clef</li>
</ul>


<p>I decided to extract 6 different parts of the exercise and this way I could practice better.</p>

<p>I practiced without schedule, some days a lot (up to one hour) some days a little (a few minutes), and even with the piano off. Anyway, the important is that all my senses get sharpened.</p>

<p>To cut it down I decided to practice individually the right and left hands. Also, I decided I would practice the measures in the following blocks and order:</p>

<ol>
<li>Measures 1,2 (the same as 3,4)</li>
<li>Measures 3</li>
<li>Measures 5,6</li>
<li>Measures 7,8</li>
<li>Measures 5 &ndash; 8</li>
<li>Measures 1 &ndash; 8</li>
<li>Measures 9,10</li>
<li>Measures 11,12</li>
<li>Measures 15,16</li>
<li> Measures 9 &ndash; 12</li>
<li> Measures 13 &ndash; 16</li>
<li> Measures 9 &ndash; 16</li>
</ol>


<p>Seems complex, but actually made me understand it better.</p>

<p>The right hand:</p>

<iframe src="http://musicpaste.com/musicapp/embed_score/mXENYyTGFekrbYWHJ7GFMy/" width="640px" height="480px"> <p>Your browser does not support iframes.</p> </iframe>


<p></p>

<p>The left hand:</p>

<iframe src="http://musicpaste.com/musicapp/embed_score/pZjXBu4aQfkhe95VRPA4M4/" width="640px" height="480px"> <p>Your browser does not support iframes.</p> </iframe>


<p></p>

<p>The whole melody (sorry about the notation that is for guitar, but VexTab doesn&rsquo;t yet support piano voices, so I&rsquo;ll put it only for you to be able to listen to the melody)</p>

<iframe src="http://musicpaste.com/musicapp/embed_score/QzbvxGvjtb7nbB4mbtsaGS/" width="640px" height="480px"> <p>Your browser does not support iframes.</p> </iframe>


<p></p>

<p>Yes, studying music takes time, and I love doing it, there is not one second I&rsquo;d rather be doing something else.</p>

<hr/>


<p>I should start recording myself and uploading the recordings &hellip; that&rsquo;s a good challenge for next week!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
